A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Administrative Functions, RG 4 FA1798
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Finance, 1950-2019; 3; 17.18 Cubic Feet 17 containers
  - Investment Reference Book, 1995-1997; 3.5; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
    - Investment Reference Book, 1995 June 1-1997 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
      Knight File Number - 206
      Prepared for Finance Committee, this book contains general investment objectives and policies, chronology of investment events from 1986 forward, portfolio performance and reports on investments. Updated quarterly.
  - Summary of Grants Paid, 1950-2009; 3.6; 0.19 Cubic Feet 1 half document box
    - List of Grants, 1950-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 203
      Alphabetical listing of grants paid from 1950 to 1995. Includes year paid, amount of grant, city, program, function, and type of organization. Updated annually.
    - List of Grants, 1950-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 2259
      List of grants paid from 1950 to 1999. List arranged by Summary of Assets and Grants, Summary of Grants by Program Area, Summary of Grants by Payment Fund and an Alphabetical Summary of Grant Paid. 2 copies
    - Historical Grant Data, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 3288
      Historical grant data. Data is for Knight Foundation grants by size; by program area and support type; national grants by program area and support type; local grants by program area and support type; and all dollars approved by city. Includes tables and figures.
    - Historical Grant Data, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 3858
    - Analysis of Endowment Grants, 2009 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 4732
      The report has three sections: 1) Analysis of endowment grants by decade - charts and tables summarize the number and amount of endowment grants by decade. They also compare endowment grants to total grants; 2) Endowments by type - provides the dollar amount of endowments by program/initiative type and 3) Endowment detail - detail listing of all endowment grants, 1980-2009.
  - Tax Returns, 1952-2018; 3.7; 9.3 Cubic Feet 24 letter document boxes and 1 half document box
    - Tax Returns, 1952-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1-24)
      Knight File Number - 207
      Federal income tax return forms 990-A, 990-T and/or 990-PF for years 1952-2018. Information includes foundation assets, expenditures, listings of grants awarded, capital gains and losses on investments, and lists of investments. Also included is information on foundation officers. The returns for 2002 and 2003 include 990-PF and 990-T returns, as well as returns for the states of California, Florida, Virginia and Kentucky (2003). Also included are 1041 returns for the years 2007 and 2008 for the Knight Trust, of which KF is a secondary beneficiary. 2008 and 2009 returns are labeled, "Public Inspection Copy". Amended returns for the years 2004-2006, filed in 2010, are in box 20. Returns for years starting 2009 are short versions only. 2016 includes original and amended 990PFs.
    - Tax Returns, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
    - Tax Returns, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Returns, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
    - Tax Returns, 1995 (continued) (Box 4A, Folder 1-4)
    - Tax Returns, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Returns, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Tax Returns, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Tax Returns, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Returns, 1999 (continued) (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Tax Returns, 1999 (continued) (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
    - Tax Returns, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - Tax Returns, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
    - Tax Returns, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Returns, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Returns, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Returns, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Returns, 2005-2006 (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Returns, 2006-2007 (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Returns, 2007-2009 (Box 19, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Returns, 2009-2012 (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
    - Tax Returns, 2013-2014 (Box 21, Folder 1-6)
      Restricted - Open in 2025
    - Tax Returns, 2015-2016 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
      Restricted - Open in 2027
    - Tax Returns, 2016-2017 (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
      Restricted - Open in 2028
    - Tax Returns, 2018 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      Restricted - Open in 2029
  - Treasurer's Report, 1990-2019; 3.8; 2.66 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes
    The Treasurer's Report is written quarterly by the Chief Financial Officer, and includes information on the Foundation's assets, investments and expenditures.
    - Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
      Knight File Number - 205
      Treasurer's reports to the board re: the financial condition of the Foundation. Includes information about independent auditors' reports, assets, portfolio performance, spending reports, stock holdings, etc. Reports are made on a quarterly basis, to coincide with board meetings. A condensed version of the treasurer's report is also available in board meeting minutes.
    - Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1998 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 1126
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 6/15/98. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 3/16/98, a portfolio summary report, and first quarter 1998 financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 1998 September 15 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 1124
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 9/15/98. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 6/14/98, a portfolio summary report, and financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 1998 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 1965
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 12/8/98. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 9/14/98, a portfolio summary report, and financial statements, and a memo from Tim Crowe to Rolfe Neill re: risk management and rogue trading..
    - Treasurer's Report, 1999 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 1966
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 3/16/99. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 12/7/98, a portfolio summary report, and an audited 1998 financial statement.
    - Treasurer's Report, 1999 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 1967
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 6/15/99. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 3/15/99, a portfolio summary report, first quarter financial statements and budget report, and a letter from Rod Petrey, Holland & Knight re: trust of Mr. & Mrs. Landon Knight.
    - Treasurer's Report, 1999 September 14 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 1968
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 9/14/99. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 6/14/99, a portfolio summary report, and second quarter 1999 financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 1999 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 1670
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 12/7/1999, in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee Meeting of September 13, 1999, third quarter 1999 portfolio summary report, and third quarter 1999 financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2000 September 10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 1671
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 9/10/2000, in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee Meeting of June 12, 2000, portfolio summary report, and second quarter 2000 financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2001 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 1854
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting (12/5/2000), a portfolio summary report for 2000 and a report from the independent auditors.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2001 June 12-December 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 2377
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees, 6/12/2001, 9/11/2001, and 12/4/2001 in Miami, FL. Includes financial statements and narrative and administrative expense summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2002 March 12-December 10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 2198
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees for the year 2002. Includes financial statements and an administrative expense summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2003 March 11-December 9 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 1969
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries. Complete for year.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2004 March 9-December 7 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 2985
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries. March report includes a report of the independent auditors (Ernst & Young) and audited financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2005 March 15-December 13 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 2986
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries. March report includes a report of the independent auditors (Ernst & Young) and audited financial statements. June report contains financial statements and general and administrative expense summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2006 March 14 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 3702
    - Treasurer's Report, 2006 June 13 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 3778
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2006 September 12 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 4518
    - Treasurer's Report, 2006 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 4048
    - Treasurer's Report, 2007 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4049
    - Treasurer's Report, 2007 June 4 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 4519
    - Treasurer's Report, 2007 September 16 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 4149
    - Treasurer's Report, 2007 December 10 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 4370
    - Treasurer's Report, 2008 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 4520
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries. Includes years ended December 21, 2007 and 2006 and a report of Independent Certified Oublic Accountants.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2008 June 9 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 4371
    - Treasurer's Report, 2008 September 14 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 4372
    - Treasurer's Report, 2008 December 8 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 4421
    - Treasurer's Report, 2009 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 4479
    - Treasurer's Report, 2009 June 8 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 4521
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements and general and administrative expense summaries. Also included are the audited financial statements for the year ended December 31, 2008. Noted was a change in how securities pledged to creditors was reported, due to changes in reporting laws.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2009 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 4575
    - Treasurer's Report, 2009 December 7 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 4644
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements, which incorporate a narrative explanation of the financial results and general and administrative expense summaries for the year to date and 3rd quarter compared to the prior year periods, as well as an analysis of 2009 projected versus 2009 budget.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2010 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 4724
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements, which incorporate a narrative explanation of the financial results and general and administrative expense summaries for the year to date and prior year.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2010 June 14 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 4755
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements, which incorporate a narrative explanation of the financial results and general and administrative expense summaries for the year to date and prior year. Also included is KF 2009 audited financial statements, along with a memo pointing out and explaining key items of interest.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2010 September 13 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 4798
    - Treasurer's Report, 2010 December 6 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 4809
    - Treasurer's Report, 2011 March 14 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4825
    - Treasurer's Report, 2011 June 13 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 4887
    - Treasurer's Report, 2011 September 11 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 4939
    - Treasurer's Report, 2011 November 22-December 12 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 4961
    - Treasurer's Report, 2012 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 5048
    - Treasurer's Report, 2012 June 11 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 5047
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements, which incorporate a narrative explanation of the financial results and general and administrative expense summaries for the year to date and prior year. Also included is a report of the Independent Auditors and audited 2011 financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2012 September 9-10 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 5091
    - Treasurer's Report, 2012 November 15-December 10 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 5317
    - Treasurer's Report, 2013 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 5144
    - Treasurer's Report, 2013 June 10 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 5191
    - Treasurer's Report, 2013 September 9 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 5323
    - Treasurer's Report, 2013 December 9 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 5269
    - Treasurer's Report, 2014 March 17 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 5288
    - Treasurer's Report, 2014 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 5361
    - Treasurer's Report, 2014 September 8 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 5388
    - Treasurer's Report, 2014 December 8 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 5470
    - Treasurer's Report, 2015 March 9 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 5533
    - Treasurer's Report, 2015 June 8 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 5550
    - Treasurer's Report, 2015 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 5616
    - Treasurer's Report, 2016 March 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 5695
    - Treasurer's Report, 2016 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 5705
      Treasurer's Reports to the Board of Trustees, prepared quarterly to coincide with the Board of Trustee meetings. Includes financial statements, which incorporate a narrative explanation of the financial results and general and administrative expense summaries for the year to date and prior year. Also included is a draft of KF's 2015 audited financial statements.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2016 September 12 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 5733
    - Treasurer's Report, 2016 November 22 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 5761
    - Treasurer's Report, 2017 March 6 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 5787
    - Treasurer's Report, 2017 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 5863
    - Treasurer's Report, 2017 September 12 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 5902
    - Treasurer's Report, 2017 December (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 5925
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees for the Board meeting on December 11, 2017; contains September 2017 financial statements with narrative; general and administrative expense summaries for year-to-date and 3rd Q
    - Treasurer's Report, 2018 March (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 5931
      Restricted - Open 2029
      Treasurer's Report for the March 12, 2018 Board of Trustees meeting. Financial statements and analysis; general and administrative expense summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2018 June (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 5936
      Treasurer's Report contains the foundation's 2017 audited financial statements and March 2018 financial statements with narrative explanation; includes general and administrative expense summaries.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2018 September (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 5938
      Treasurer's Report for the September 17, 2018 Board of Trustees meeting contains the June 2018 financial statements, and the general and administrative expenses summaries for the year to date and Q2.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2018 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 5942
      Treasurer's Report presented to the Board of Trustees meeting on December 10, 2018. Financial statements and analysis; general and administrative expense summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2019 March 11 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 5947
      Treasurer's Report to the Board of Trustees on March 11, 2019. Financial statements and analysis; general and administrative expenses summary and analysis.
    - Treasurer's Report, 2019 June 10 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 5953
      Treasurer's Report for the Board of Trustees Meeting on June 10, 2019. Cover memo; report of independent auditors and audited 2018 financial statements; financial statements and analysis; general and administrative expense summary and analysis
    - Treasurer's Report, 2019 September 9 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 5959
      Treasurer's Report prepared for the September 9, 2019 Board of Trustees meeting. Contains June 2019 financial statements; general and administrative expense summareis for 2nd quarter and year-to-date
    - Treasurer's Report, 2019 December 9 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 5962
      Treasurer's Report prepared for the Board of Trustees meeting on December 9, 2019. Contain September 2019 financial statements; general and administrative expense summaries for the 3rd quarter and year-to-date
  - Administrative Files, 1982-1996; 3.9; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
    - Excess Business Holdings related to James L. Knight's Estate, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-10, Box 2, Folder 1-6)
      Knight File Number - 1539
      Two items: a memo from Tim Crowe to the Finance Committee and a confidential letter to Creed Black from Rod Petrey, legal counsel, both regarding excess business holdings of Knight-Ridder stock related to the bequest from the James L. Knight Estate.
    - IRS Audit of Knight Foundation's 1991 return, 1995 April 3-1996 September 3 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4778
      Correspondence and documents relating to an IRS audit of the Foundation's 1991 tax return. The issues investigated included 501(c)(3) status of some of the grantees, withholding taxes for consultants and employees, and the Knight trusts.